Guide to the Arch Brown papers, circa 1955-2012.
Brown, Arch papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Arch Brown papers, circa 1955-2012.
7799
Brown, Arch.
12 cubic feet., 26.77 gigabytes.
Photographs, printed materials, publications, videos
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of personal memorabilia and biographical materials, manuscripts of plays and novels, scripts, news clippings and scrapbooks, audio-visual recordings and personal photographs as well as professional erotic photography.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Born and raised in Chicago, Arch Brown attended Northwestern University where he studied under the legendary Alvina Krause and was graduated with a B.S. in Theatre and Television. Almost immediately after graduation, he was invited to move to New York City to join the staff of The Circle in the Square Theatre where he became the Design and Technical Assistant on Children of Darkness, The Quare Fellow and Our Town. During his early years in New York he also designed several musical revues at The Duplex, The Showplace and Upstairs at the Downstairs. He has also worked as a steel warehouse foreman, an insurance adjuster and a model. In retailing he was a display director, a fashion coordinator and a merchandise manager. He was the designer for the D'Arni-Gould Sportswear line. With his life-partner, Bruce Allen Brown, he was a real estate investor in New York City and owner/manager of Sea Park St. Croix, a hotel in the U.S. Virgin Islands. Arch Brown's still photographs and collages have appeared in Mandate, Honcho, The Village Voice, Michael's Thing and The Union Seminary Quarterly Review and at The Underground Gallery. His essays and reviews have appeared in The Advocate, The Villager, Manhattan G.A.Z.E. and he had a regular column on "Television and Society" in the New York Native. He was the founder of G-MAN, The Gay Men's Arts Network and, in memory of Bruce Brown who died in 1993 of a brain hemorrhage, he sponsored The Arch and Bruce Brown Foundation which gives grants to gay-positive arts projects based on history. Arch Brown's double biography of his life with Bruce was published in Longtime Companions by Haworth Press. Brown first came to broad public attention through his films. During gay liberation's closet-busting first decade, Brown's homoerotic films (including Four Letters, Pier Groups, The Super, Trips, Harley's Angels, Longjohns, The Tool Man, After the Fall, The Leather Bond, Dynamite!, All Tied Up, Rough Idea, and Woodshole achieved an international following and superb reviews. His film "The Night Before" was on Variety's 50 top-grossing films in the nation for 5 weeks. Brown's film Tuesday was the only gay film included by the First New York Erotic Film Festival in its nation-wide release of winning films. The distributors were charged with promoting obscenity. His film "Sunday" won first prize in the Park Miller Eros Competition. Brown also has directed several documentary films on art and culture including a series on English as a Second Language for New York University. In 1979, at the suggestion of a friend who recognized the wit in his films, Brown turned to playwriting. His first play, News Boy, was produced later that year by The GLINES, went on to a full Off-Broadway mounting at the Player's Theatre and had nine productions across the country over the next 15 years. Brown's play, FREEZE! won the 1998 Eric Bentley Playwriting Prize. Other published and/or produced plays include; Two Married Men, Samson, Sex Symbols, Brut Farce, Seeing Red, Breakfast with Ferkin and Frank, Doubletalk and Ships That Piss in the Night. Arch Brown died peacefully at his home in Palm Springs on September 3, 2012. Taken from the Arch Brown website http://www.archbrown.com/bio.html, accessed on September 2014.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of personal memorabilia and biographical materials, manuscripts of plays and novels, scripts from his own plays as well as from plays put on by the Thorny Theater, news clippings and scrapbooks, audio-visual recordings and personal photographs as well as professional erotic photography. Collection also includes the business records belonging to the Thorny Theater in Palm Springs, CA owned by Arch Brown as well as posters, flyers and other promotional materials relating to productions of his plays at various theaters across the country.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brown, Arch.
Subjects:
Drama.; Pornographic films.; Photography, Erotic.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 14 is restricted to permission of the donor..
NOTES
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Materials
Series II. Photography
Prints and Negatives
Slides
Series III. Manuscripts
Play Scripts
Other Manuscript and Printed Material
Series IV. Theater and Bruce and Arch Brown Foundation
Production Material
Thorny Theater
Posters, Flyers and Other Promotional Materials
Series V. Media
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Materials
  - Miscellaneous Keepsakes, c. 1953-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence, cards, commencement program, news letters
  - Miscellaneous Keepsakes, c. 1959-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Envelope with personal documents
  - Northeastern University diploma and photo, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Family History, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Email correspondence. Includes photo of Arch Brown
  - Parents - photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - School and childhood photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Personal and family photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Very Early Photographs", 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Production photographs, c. 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    College production. Most likely from the Drama Department at Northwestern University
  - "Our Baby's Early Years", 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Childhood photographs and programs, 1938-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1936-1954 (Box 2, Volume 1)
    Oversize
  - Photo Album, 1936-1963 (Box 2, Volume 2)
  - "The 15th International Youth Conference in Boston Mass.", 1953 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Programs for plays, 1955, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Catching Personalities in Pictures" photo album, undated (Box 2, Volume 3)
    Includes some other photos tipped in to the front page. Oversize.
  - "1966", 1965-1990s (Box 2, Volume 4)
    Photograph Album marked "1966" but actually spans a period from the mid 1960s to the early 1990s. Appearing in the Album: Merrill Cleghorne - African American gay artist and friend of Arch Brown.
    Nude photo of Bruce Brown. Early vacations in San Juan and the lakeside cottage Arch and Bruce owned in Connecticut in the 1960s - 1970s.
    Also shows Bruce and Arch Brown in a Manhattan rental apartment in the 1960s and their apartment on 14th Street in New York City in the 1970s
    Bruce at the house they owned in Phoenix, Arizona in the late 1980s - early 1990s
    Bruce after having suffered a massive stroke.
  - Modeling photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Arch Brown under his given name Arnold Krueger
  - Window display photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Arch Brown worked a display artist before becoming a photographer and pornographer.
  - Note book, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Written in two hands. Most of the writing is by Bruce Brown. Several of the people mentioned in the notebook remained lifelong friends.
  - Clinton Hill Materials, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Arch and Bruce Brown owned a house on Layfayette Avenue in Clinton Hill in the 1970's when the neighborhood was just then gentrifying.
  - "Work Uniforms", Late 1970s-early 1980s (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Photograph Album.
    Appearing in the album: Arch Brown, Bruce Brown, Lester Bower (in drag as Alice Frederica Keppel, mistress of Edward VII,) John David Earnest, the porn actor "Scorpio," and unknown others.
    At least one photo was taken at the loft on West 14th Street in New York City belonging to Arch and Bruce Brown.
  - A Celebration of the Life, Love and Freedom of Salatore J. Licata, Ph.D., 1990 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    Photograph and Memorial Album
    Mentioned in the memorial program: Rev. Bill Johnson Michael Shernoff, Arnie Kantrowitz, Rev. Al Carmines, Rebeccca Porper, Mark Mutchnik, Jane Rosett, Martin Worman, Pat LaMariana.
    Appearing in the album: Bruce and Arch Brown, Sal Licata, his partner, David Summers, and unknown others.
  - "Mrs. Claus", undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Photograph Album
  - Christmas card from Arch Brown, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - People: Recent Paintings by Jonathan Weinberg, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Signed by artist
  - Brussels, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Personal travel photos
  - Arrowhead, divination pendulum and herbal sachet charms, undated; MU-2091-2093 (Box 1)
  - Medical X-Rays, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Portraits of Arch Brown collage, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Series II. Photography
  - Prints and Negatives from Porn Shoots - c.1968-1984
    - Actor, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bad Complected Blond, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Billy C., c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bill S., c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bill Shitty, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Black, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      See "White" Box 3, Folder 15
    - Black and White Carpenters, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Black Reggie, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bleached Blond, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Blond on Chaise, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bosch, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Charlie and ?, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Chubb on Sofa, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Claude on Fire Island, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Eric Hill, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Fire Island Model, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Frank, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Frank - 2nd Set, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Frank C. and Rick and Jess, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Gaytony, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Harley's Angels, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Stills and cast shots from Arch Brown film
    - Irishman, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Jan, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Jeff Gonld, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Jim S., c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Jim Sibal - Bear, c. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Karl's "Muscle Bound", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Production shots of the Arch Brown film "Muscle Bound"
    - Karl's "Muscle Bound", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Production shots.
    - Karl's "Muscle Bound", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Luc, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mac, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Michael and Allen, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Michael Boyd, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Peter, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Peter De, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Peter, Eric, White, Rom, Dick, Bosch, Jan (1), 1970s (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Erotic photos
    - Peter, Eric, White, Rom, Dick, Bosch, Jan (2), 1970s (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Richard Bald, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Rick, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Rob Fry, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Ron, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Scorpio, Will, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Sibal and Gree - Apostles, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Sister Mary Kodak, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Sister Mary Kodak, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Contact sheets for the Negatives in Folder 13
    - Halloween (1981) and Sister Mary Kodak, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Takacs and Richard, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - White, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      See "Black" Box 1, Folder 19
    - unlabeled, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - unlabeled, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - unlabeled, c. 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - unlabeled, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Possibly from one of Arch Brown's straight porn films
  - Prints and Negatives from Porn Shoots and Personal. Erotic and Non-Erotic
    - Loose Prints (1), c. late 1960s-early 1980s (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Erotic photos.
      Cast photos of early Arch Brown play from the late 1970s or early 1980s.
      Snapshot of Arch and Bruce Brown for the 1960s
    - Plays and Films (1-3), c. early 1970s (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
      Head shots of actors and stills from porn films
    - Island, etc (1), early to mid 1970s (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Island, etc (2), early to mid 1970s (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Also includes nude men on West Side (Manhattan) piers, Fire Island and other locations.
    - Island, etc (3), early to mid 1970s (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Includes photos of Arch Brown, Bruce Brown, monuments, cats and interiors.
    - Bruce Brown, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Men (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
      In box marked "Men" but this folder contains non-erotic subjects - museums, monuments, cats etc.
    - Men (2), 1970s (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Beach and town shots of Cherry Grove, Fire Island
    - Men (3), 1970s (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Erotic photos of Bruce Brown and other models, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Contact sheets
    - Unlabeled Box (1), 1970s (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Erotic photos, travel, and portraits
    - Unlabeled Box (2), c. 1940s and 1970s (Box 3, Folder 37)
      Erotic photos, travel and 1 childhood photo of Arch Brown
    - Black and White Pictures and Contacts, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Loose Prints (2), 1970s-2000s (Box 3, Folder 39)
      2 sheets of negatives. Erotic photos from the 1970s.
      Cast photos pf early Arch Brown plays from the 1980s.
      S and M photos of Bernd from the 1990s.
      Thorny Theater cast photos from the 2000s
    - Landscapes (1), 1970s-early 1980s (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Touristic shots of Mexico, Washington D.C., New York City and elsewhere
    - Landscapes (2), 1970s-early 1980s (Box 3, Folder 41)
      Touristic shots of New York City (Manhattan)
      Includes a portrait of Arch filming "Tray" - Tray Christopher (aka Christopher Rage) another gay-porn filmmaker and sometime collaborator.
    - First News Boy (1-2), c. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 42-43)
      Cast and production photos of Arch Brown's first production (off-off- Broadway) of News Boy
    - Chicago IML [RESTRICTED], 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Buck and Gree - Angels [RESTRICTED], 1990s (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Photos of Arch Brown and Buck Bove
    - Bernd, c. 1990s (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Bernd, a German architect, was one of Arch Brown's last long-term boyfriends who committed suicide in the late 1990s or early 2000s.
    - Bernd, c. 1990s (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Bernd, 14th Street, c. 1990s (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Bernd in Hotel, c. 1990s (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Publicity Shots, 1990s-2000s (Box 3, Folder 48)
      Photographs of Arch Brown, including later sex snaps in his late 60s early 70s).
    - LA (San Bernadino) and Palm Springs, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Contact Sheets and Negatives (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Contact Sheets and Negatives (2), undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
      Negatives
    - Contact Sheets and Negatives (3), undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Arch Brown business cards found with scrapbook in box 14, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Matted Photo Collage, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Photos of models and Arch Brown lovers, including Bruce Brown, Buck Bove, Bernd, James Waller
    - Large Prints, c. 1970s-1990s, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Photos of Bernd
      Architectural photos
      Photo montage from the film "The Country
    - Large Prints, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Erotic and portrait photographs.
      Collages.
      Tom of Finland prints.
      Cast photo of Arch Brown Film "Muscle Bound"
      Touristic photos including from the National Gallery in Washington DC
    - Large Prints, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Mainly photocopies/Caricature drawing of Arch Brown by "BA" possibly from the 1980s
    - Artwork, c. 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Photo collages. Includes Black and White stats of 2 collages made by Arch Brown for the "Union Seminary Quarterly Review issue on nuclear war.
    - "The Country", early 1970s (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Pages from a photograph album. Possibly from a film "The Country" made by Arch Brown in the arly 1970s and Arch and Bruce Brown's country/lakeside house in Connecticut
    - Pages from a photograph album, 1970s, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 9)
      1 leaf of photos of Bernd (1990s)
    - Scrapbook, c. 1973-1993 (Box 6)
      Contains clippings about Arch Brown's movies and plays.
      Back pocket contains the magazines "Hot'n'Hung"; "Man's Country" and "Hot Ones"
    - Photograph album [RESTRICTED], undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Loose pages from a scrapbook.
    - Photo collage [RESTRICTED], undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Photographs of Buck Bove
  - Slides - Personal and Erotic
    - Slides - Men, c. 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      Includes photos commissioned by gay slicks portraying bondage
    - Slides - FWD and C, c. 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Spain (1-2), c. 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Cottage; Mexico '73; Bonaire; Jamaica; Charleston; Florida; Virginia, c. 1971-1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Italy (and Spain, Tunisia, and Greece), c. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Tunisia, c. 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Browns - Fire Island, c. 1972 and 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Fire Island, c. 1974 and 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Fire Island and the Country, c. 1974 and 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Greece, c. 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Greece and M. Dunn and Chuck, c. 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Amalfi, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Florence, c. 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - San Marino, c. 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Sienna, c. 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Sirmione, c. 1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Venice, c. 1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - C. Bond; LTHR Duo; Pier Groups, c. 1978, 1984, and undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Includes bondage/dildo slides and stills from Arch Brown's film "Pier Groups" (1979)
    - Long Johns - Good Backups, c. 1979, 1981, and undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Dick and Eric, c. 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Michael and Chuck, c. 1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Michael Pen and Ron, c. 1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Halloween, c. 1981 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Michael, c. 1981 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Scorpio, c. 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Scorp(io) and Don, c. 1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Edward and Alexandera, c. 1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      Arch Brown and Bruce Brown in costume as Edward VII and Queen Alexandra
    - Sex Symbols, c. 1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      Scenes from Arch Brown's second produced play (off-off Broadway) "Sex Symbols"
    - Bosch, c. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Rough Idea and Frank and Steinecki, c. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Scenes from "Rough Idea" (1984), possibly Arch Brown's last porn film.
    - St. Croix - Sea Park (1 and 2), c. 1986 (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
      Bed and Breakfast/Hotel owned and run by Arch and Bruce Brown in St. Croix, US Virgin Islands in the 1980s
    - Sea Park (1), c. 1986 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Sea Park (2 and 3), c. 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32-33)
    - Sea Park Promos (1 and 2), c. 1988 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
    - St. Croix, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 49)
      Sea Park
    - Top Story, c. 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      Cast photos and scenes from Arch Brown's video "Top Story" produced in Phoenix, Arizona in 1992 or 1993
    - NYC Freeze! (1 and 2), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
      Cast photos and scenes from Arch Brown play "Freeze!" production (off-off Broadway)
    - Untitled (NYC Freeze!), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      Cast photos and scenes.
    - Loose Slides (Jamie and NYC Freeze!), undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Jamie (1 and 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
    - Long Johns (1-5), undated (Box 4, Folder 39-43)
    - Nick, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Manuscripts
  - Play Scripts
    - "Atlantic City", 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Under the name Arnold Krueger. Not produced and unpublished
    - "After", undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Fragment of play self-published in "Heavy Hangers" collection of plays.
      Note: Plays in the "Heavy Hangers" collection are sequenced chronologically but the plays were not written in that order; chronology was imposed later. Originally written as individual plays, then reconceived as a series.
    - "Samson" or "Sam's Son", 1980-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Produced in New York City and self-published in "Heavy Hangers" collection of plays.
      Partly based on letters exchanged between Arch Brown and James Waller in 1982-1983 (dated 1977-1978 in the play)
    - "Samson" or "Sam's Son", 1980-1989 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      2nd copy
    - "News Boy", undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Manuscript of Arch Brown's first and most commercially successful play.
      Self-published in "Heavy Hangers" collection of plays.
    - "Sex Symbols", undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Arch Brown's second play, produced off-off Broadway.
    - "Breakfast with Ferkin and Farelli", undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Never produced. Self-published in "Heavy Hangers" collection of plays.
    - "Comeback", undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
      2 copies. Never produced. Self-published in "Heavy Hangers" collection of plays.
    - "Seeing Red", undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Two Married Men", undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Incomplete. Produced. Self-published in "Heavy Hangers" collection of plays.
    - "News Boy", undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Printed Copy
    - unknown - missing title page, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Sex Symbols", undated (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
    - "Two Married Men", undated (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
    - "Two Married Men", c. 2009 (Box 7, Volume 1)
      In binder with other Thorny Theater materials
    - "Samson", undated (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
      Cast member scripts. With Notes
    - "The Dying Fall of Eric Tarr, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      By Arch Brown and Joseph Hansen. Never produced.
    - "The Dying Fall of Eric Tarr, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Red Rod", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      Never produced.
    - "Red Rod", 1990 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Church Island Woman, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "Freeze!", undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
      Original 1st version
    - "Freeze!", undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
      Original 2nd version. Published and produced at least 2x, in New York City and Palm Springs.
    - "Freeze!", 1996 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - "Freeze!", undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - "Freeze!", undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
      With notations.
    - "Freeze!", 1995 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - "Freeze!", 1996 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - "Freeze!", 1997 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - "Freeze!", 1997 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      With cover note.
    - "Doubletalk", 1997 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      Jean Caussin copy
    - "Doubletalk", 1997, undated (Box 7, Folder 31-33)
      2 versions
    - "Pantheon", 2000 (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
      2 versions.
    - "Pantheon", undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
      Printed version; stage designs, incomplete script
    - "Pantheon", 2000 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      With cover letter to James Waller.
    - "Variations on a Scheme", 2002 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - "Variations on a Scheme", 2002 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      Title page changed to "Edward II by Christopher Marlow." 2 copies
    - The Bottom Drawer, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 39-40)
      2 versions. Autobiographical play based on Arch Brown's relationship with his parents, particularly his mother.
    - "Hypotenuse", c. 1970s (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Very early play.
    - Peace by Piece, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Printed version.
    - Peace by Piece, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)